

#### **PERSONAL**

- Name
  SK Choo
- ★ Address Ampang Selangor
- **Phone number** +6016-3967067
- Email ivan.skchoo@gmail.com
- Date of birth 22-09-1983
- **Gender** Male
- Nationality
  Malaysian
- Marital status
  Single
- www.linkedin.com/in/ivan-choo-65902013b

### **LANGUAGES**

English Mandarin Malay



# SK CHOO

Senior validation engineer with 15 years of experience on manual and automated software testing. Expertise on STLC (Software Testing Life Cycle) processes and different types of frontend and backend testing, that caught up various critical software defects and delivered quality product releases. Integration of automation testing tools (GUI and API) in Python which saved up half of the efforts from manual testing.

Sincerely looking for the testing job opportunities as QA team lead for the embedded Desktop software, or test engineer for the web-based application.



### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Dec 2009 - Present

### **Senior Validation Engineer**

HexoSys SDN BHD, KL

### Testing lead for Teledyne LeCroy SAS/SATA Protocol Suite

Expertise in STLC (Software Testing Life Cycle) for product requirement analysis according to the marketing expectation, test planning with the given resources to meet the release schedule, test management for designing high bug-detection test scenarios, test cases execution in different environments, and release document preparation for the bug tracking and coverage details. Experiences in different testing types including unit testing, integration testing, smoke testing, user acceptance testing, system testing, regression testing, usability testing, performance testing and security testing. Collaboration with different teams including project management team for status update, software development team for fix review, support team for the customer's issue inspection, and validation team for the supervision and test analysis.

Development of automation test for frontend (GUI with Squish tool) and backend (API with Link Expert tool) which saved up to 50% of the manual testing efforts.

# Senior software tester for Teledyne LeCroy Net/FC and PCIe Protocol Suite

Comprehension in product protocols analysis, high-speed traffic generators, different testing and automation tools, and familiarity of Agile software development process in Jenkins CI/CD and Sprint approach.

Self-developed skillset on the webpage UI testing with Selenium webdriver,

Self-developed skillset on the webpage UI testing with Selenium webdriver web-service REST API testing with Postman and performance testing with Jmeter.

Feb 2017 - Dec 2018 Part-time Property Negotiator

KLCT International Realty SDN BHD, KL

Comprehension of market analysis, online marketing techniques, sale and purchase transaction workflow.

Ability to communicate, negotiate and deal with different clients.

Dec 2008 - Dec 2009 Post-Silicon Validation Engineer

Intel Microelectronics (M) SDN BHD, Penang

Delivery of post-silicon test content including the test generation, testing, debug and improvement.

Learning on Python programming, hardware testing and hardware communication scripting.

Jun 2008 - Nov 2008 Automation Engineer

Intel Microelectronics (M) SDN BHD, Penang

Comprehension of CERT (CADNav test regression tool) in UNIX environment for test creation, test execution, test validation and debug.

Development of CERT automated tests.



## **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

Jun 2005 - Jun 2008 Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical/Electronic)

Universiti Teknologi Malaysia, Johor

**Subject studied** 

Circuit Theory, Electronic Digit, Micro Processor, VLSI, Artificial Intelligence, Digital System, Electronics and Electromagnetic, C and C++, Data Structure,

Assembly, Verilog. **Final-year project** 

Video processing system with Verilog programming.

**GPA** 3.45.

2018 - Present Foundation Level ISTQB Certificate

MSTB (Malaysian Software Testing Board), KL

Fundamentals of software testing including key concepts, testing techniques,

test management and testing tools.

2008 - Present VLSI Training Programme

Multimedia Development Corporation (MDeC), Penang

Functional design, Circuit design, Logic design and Physical design.



# **REFERENCES**

Teledyne LeCroy Wolfgang Fueg (Validation manager)

+1408-886-8986 fueg99@me.com

HexoSys Mohammad Adzani (Team manager)

+6012-4060995

mohammad@hexosys.com



# **SKILLS**

Manual testing

Automated testing

Frontend testing

Backend testing

Programming

★★★★

★★★★



# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

HexoSys's Performance Award - Dec 2013 and Sep 2017 Intel's Department Level Award - Aug 2009